petmd.com 2018-02-04

# PETMD PRIVACY POLICY | petMD

**Last Updated: January 29, 2016**

PetMD, LLC ("PetMD") provides a network of content and e-commerce websites, mobile applications and other online platforms dedicated to making Pet Parenting easier through a highly personalized experience that offers convenience and resources to enhance Pet Parenthood. This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by PetMD, and its parent, sister, subsidiary or affiliated companies, when you explore or interact with our content or make purchases on our websites, mobile applications or online platforms. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our websites, mobile applications or online platforms and any other online products and services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Services") or when you otherwise interact with us.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you a notification). We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

### Collection of Information

_Information You Provide to Us_

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you: register for an account; make a purchase; subscribe to our newsletters or other emails; fill out a form; participate in a contest, survey, or chat room; return or exchange a product; participate in any interactive features of the Services; ask questions of us or our veterinarians or vet techs; apply for a job; request customer support; contact our call center; or otherwise communicate with us. The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, postal address, phone number, fax number, credit card information, information about your pet (including the pet’s name, breed, gender, age, and photo), and any other information you choose to provide. If you place an order that requires a prescription, we collect information about your Veterinarian so that we may confirm the prescription and fill your order. We may also collect information about gift recipients such as name, email address, and shipping address so that we can fulfill the gift purchase. The information we collect about gift recipients is used for purposes of sending the gift and will not be used for other purposes.

_Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Services_

When you access or use our Services, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * **Log Information:** We collect log information about your use of the Services including, but not limited to, the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, your device type, the operating system you are using, the page you visited before navigating to our Services and any other related information.
  * **Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** We and our service providers collect information using various technologies, including cookies and web beacons. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us improve our Services and your experience, store your preferences, manage your shopping cart, provide more relevant advertising, see which areas and features of our Services are popular and count visits. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits and understand usage and campaign effectiveness. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see "Your Choices" below.

_Information We Collect From Other Sources_

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our Services. For example, if you create or log into the Services through a social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, email address, and other information provided in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site. We may also obtain information about you from list brokers and publicly-available sources.

### Use of Information

We may use information about you for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain and improve our Services;
  * Provide and deliver the products you order, process transactions, and send you related information, including confirmations and invoices,
  * If you place an order that requires a prescription, to contact your Veterinarian, confirm the prescription, and fill your order.
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions, and requests and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards, and events offered by PetMD and others, including our affiliated companies, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Personalize and improve the Services and provide advertisements, content, or features that match user profiles or interests;
  * Process and deliver surveys, contest entries, and rewards; and
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs and provide you with better service.

PetMD is based in the United States and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the U.S. and other countries.

### Sharing of Information

We may share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf;
  * With third parties for their own marketing purposes, unless you opt out of this type of sharing by following the opt-out instructions under “Your California Privacy Rights,” below];
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of PetMD or others;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company;
  * Between and among the PetMD web properties and the PetMD parent, sister, subsidiaries and affiliated companies; and
  * With your consent or at your direction.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.

Finally, note that any content posted in public chatrooms or question and answer forums may be read, collected, and used by others, and PetMD is not responsible for that activity. For example, search engines may index your questions, answers, and other posts to allow them to appear in search engine results. We recommend that you not include your real name or any personally identifying information in your questions, answers, and other posts.

### Social Sharing Features and Surveys

The Services may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools, which let you share actions you take or articles you enjoy on our Services with other media, and vice versa. Your use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

You may also be asked to participate in surveys about your experience(s) with the Services. These surveys may be conducted by our third-party partners. The collection, use and storage of any data associated with surveys conducted by such third parties is governed by such partner’s privacy policy.

### Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others

We may allow others to provide analytics services and serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and in applications. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers and other technologies to collect information about your use of the PetMD web properties and Services and those of our affiliates, and other websites and applications. The information these entities may collect includes your IP address, web browser, mobile network information, pages viewed, time spent on pages or in apps, links clicked, and information about actions you took when you saw or clicked on an ad. This information may be used by PetMD, our affiliates, and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services, our affiliates’ services, and other websites and services and better understand your online activity. Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. Neither PetMD nor its third party providers have a systematic method for ensuring that browser “Do Not Track” requests are consistently honored. However, you may learn more about online advertising and opt out of the use of your web browsing activity to serve targeted ads by companies that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance by visiting [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). You can also disable cookies in your browser, as described below.

We may also work with other websites or platforms (such as Facebook) to serve ads to you as part of a customized campaign, unless you notify us that you prefer not to have information about you used in this way. To opt out, [click here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

### Security

PetMD takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

### Children

The Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not provide any information through the Services, make any purchases through the Services, or use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Services. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us here, or write us at PetMD, LLC, Attn: Privacy Policy, 2260 Butler Pike, Plymouth Meeting, PA 19462.

### Your Choices

#### **Account Information**

You may update, correct or delete information about you at any time by logging into your online account. If you wish to delete your account, please contact us here, but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time.

#### **Cookies and Locally Stored Objects**

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies and certain locally stored objects, like Web storage, by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies and some locally stored objects. However, these browser settings will not necessarily affect third party flash cookies used in connection with our Services. To delete or disable Flash cookies please visit [http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) for more information. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies or locally stored objects, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services. Currently, our systems do not recognize browser "do-not-track" signals.

#### **Promotional Communications**

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from PetMD by following the instructions in those emails. You may also opt out of promotional emails and postal mailings by clicking here to unsubscribe. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account, orders, or our ongoing business relations.

#### **Your California Privacy Rights**

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please contact us here, or write us at: PetMD, LLC, Attn: Privacy Policy, 2260 Butler Pike, Plymouth Meeting, PA 19462. However, please note that under the law, Services such as ours that permit California residents to opt out of this type of sharing are not required to provide such information upon receiving a request, but rather may respond by notifying the user of his or her right to prevent the disclosure. To opt out of having information about you shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes, please [click here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us here.
